Guide to the Patent Cereals Company records, 1888-1957.
Patent Cereals Company records, 1888-1957.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Patent Cereals Company records, 1888-1957.
1931
Patent Cereals Company.
.8 cubic ft.
Minutes, reports, correspondence, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records of this Geneva, New York, company, which processed cereal products chiefly for the brewing industry, include minutes of annual stockholders' meetings and meetings of the Board of Directors; auditor's reports and treasurer's reports; correspondence; annual reports; and other legal and business papers, some concerning the sale of the firm to the Lauhoff Grain Company of Danville, Illinois.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records of this Geneva, New York, company, which processed cereal products chiefly for the brewing industry, include minutes of annual stockholders' meetings and meetings of the Board of Directors; auditor's reports and treasurer's reports; correspondence; annual reports; and other legal and business papers, some concerning the sale of the firm to the Lauhoff Grain Company of Danville, Illinois.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Patent Cereals Company.; Lauhoff Grain Company (Danville, Ill.)
Subjects:
Brewing industry.; Cereal products industry--New York (State)--Geneva.; Industries--New York (State)--Geneva.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PARTIAL CONTAINER LIST
- Minute books
  - I. Sept. 9, 1888-Jan. 9, 1903 (Box 1-2)
  - II. Mar. 23, 1903-July 18, 1908 (Box 1-2)
  - III. Sept. 20, 1908-July 12, 1918 (Box 1-2)
  - IV. Dec. 9, 1918-June 1, 1923 (Box 1-2)
  - V. Dec. 10, 1923-Dec. 9, 1929 (Box 1-2)
  - VI. Dec. 9, 1929-Dec. 11, 1935 (Box 1-2)
  - VII. Mar. 1936-Dec. 1937 (Box 1-2)
  - VIII. Mar. 1938-Dec. 1945 (Box 1-2)
  - IX. Mar. 1946-Dec. 1950 (Box 1-2)
  - X. 1951-1954 (black looseleaf notebook) (Box 1-2)
    Includes minutes of annual meetings of stockholders, quarterly meetings of the board of directors, and a special meeting held in Apr. 1954 having to do with the proposed purchase of the Comstock Canning Company
  - XI. 1955-1957 (leather volume) (Box 1-2)
    Includes minutes of 1955 annual stockholders meeting and quarterly meetings of board of directors for same year, as well as minutes of special meetings and 1956 and 1957 minutes of Assets Realization Co.; also, by-laws of Patent Cereals Company of correspondence re: its sale.
- Record book titled "Minutes - Special Meeting" (paper covered binder) (Box 1-2)
  Includes depositions, schedule of stockholders as of Mar. 9, 1956, printed items such as notices to stockholders, CPA's report, and purchase agreement; also, agenda for and minutes of special meeting of Apr. 10, 1956, mimeo. proxy ballots, and election inspectors' certificate and oath.
- Record book titled "Papers Relating to Lauhoff Transfer ..." (paper covered binder) (Box 1-2)
  Includes letters from Kernan & Kernan, Attorneys, Utica, Mar.-Apr. 1956, concerning this transfer, to John F. Carroll, Secretary, and to Frederick L. King, President. Also, typescript copy of ballot; cc of letter from K&K to Internal Revenue office in Buffalo; assignment agreement whereby Lauhoff Grain Company of Illinois assigned to Lauhoff of Delaware its rights and liabilities under Mar. 16, 1956 purchase agreeement with Patent Cereals; agreement re: change of name of Patent Cereals Company to Assets Realization Company, Inc.; copies of various legal forms, some blank, presumably duplicate.